[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">Dearest gentle reader,
I must send felicitations
to the new Duke and Duchess of Hastings.
Congratulations and stamina
as they embark
on the most exhilarating time
in a young couple's life.
I am, of course, talking of the honeymoon.
[horses neighing]
Is there a more romantic notion?
-To retreat from society together…
<span style="style1">-Good morning.
-…finally leaving watchful eyes behind.
Welcome to Clyvedon, Your Grace.
It has been so long
since we have been blessed
with your presence,
but I trust
you will find everything to your liking.
I do not doubt it, Mrs. Colson.
I hope you have been well.
Mm.
May I introduce to you
the Duchess of Hastings?
I am looking forward
to making your acquaintance, Mrs. Colson.
Thank you, Your Grace.
I have planned everything
to make you both comfortable.
First, a light meal,
served on the terrace.
Then a tour to show you
all the improvements I have made. Then--
I am sure it will be most diverting,
but I am afraid it will have to wait.
I have plans of my own for my new bride.
Mm.
[chuckles]
I want to show you the bedroom.
Yours or mine?
You truly believe
we are to have separate rooms?
I should think not.
[both chuckling] Stop! They shall see!
Whatever will they think?
Does it matter?
[Daphne laughs]
[Simon laughs]
[Lady Whistledown]<span style="style2"> While this author,
<span style="style2">along with the rest of the ton,
will certainly miss
its most-remarked-upon couple
back in London,
perhaps we might find solace
in the promise of the duke and duchess
returning to us bearing a surprise.
[crowd chattering]
I wonder what Daphne is doing
at this very moment.
I am sure she has many new duties
to attend to as duchess,
things you should be learning
for your debut.
[Eloise scoffs]
Making simpering conversation,
pretending not to wince
every time a man treads
on my toes during a waltz?
-Eloise!
-I'm no good at those things.
I'll only make a fool of myself.
If you devoted as much time
to your deportment lessons
as you did to writing in your journal,
you might feel rather better.
And on that subject,
in preparation for your season,
it is time we lowered your skirts
to wear at home.
I have no time
for a visit to the modiste.
I am busy.
The queen herself has charged me
with discovering Whistledown's identity.
You would not have me cross
Her Majesty, would you?
-[glass clanging]
-May I have everyone's attention?
I would like to make a small
but important announcement.
I have happy news to impart.
I have asked Miss Marina Thompson
to be my wife, and she has accepted.
[guests exclaim happily]
[applause]
[woman] Congratulations!
[guests laughing, chattering]
[man] Bravo, sir!
Did you know about this?
People are looking, dear.
Congratulate the happy couple.
You barely know the young lady.
What were you thinking?
I was thinking you'd respond like this
and how little I would care to hear.
Do you think this is a joke?
Poor Mother was beside herself.
Mother seems perfectly happy to me.
She congratulated us.
So, you compromised this young lady?
-Certainly not. I am a gentleman.
-Then why ever would you--
Why does anyone marry, brother?
For love, of course.
Look, I know you are still rather green,
and that is my fault.
I should've taken you to brothels
when you returned from Eton.
If this is a matter
of wetting your wick--
You are an ass. Do you know that?
This is what comes
of not sowing your wild oats.
Proposing to the first chit
you set your cap at.
Enough!
You insult me and my intended.
It is not my fault, nor Marina's,
that you cannot fathom true attachment.
-You are still a child, Colin.
-I'm older than Daphne.
-You were happy to marry her off.
-It is not the same.
-I know nothing of the sort.
-Then you betray your immaturity!
If<span style="style2"> I caused Mother discomfort today,
I am sorry for it.
I shall speak with her.
The truth is, I do not require
your permission to marry Miss Thompson…
but I would very much prefer
to have your blessing.
Then I am afraid I must disappoint you.
You have…
in more ways than one.
[door opens, closes]
[theme music plays]
I believe I now know the reason
why every mama of the ton keeps
her daughter in total darkness
about certain… diversions.
[Simon] Mm.
Do you?
[chuckles] Should they have told us
what it was truly like,
however would we get
anything else done at all?
[laughs]
-[Simon kissing]
-[moans lightly]
-I must go.
-Mm.
If I am to be duchess of all of this,
I must start learning the lie of the land.
You are already duchess of all this.
-[Simon chuckles]
-And I look forward
to exploring that particular land further…
-Later.
-[both laughing]
Simon!
You said the duchy was most intimidating.
Why not stay and lord it over this room?
You may find it a bit more titillating.
[laughs] I do not doubt it.
But I suspect
Mrs. Colson shall always resent me
if I do not take her tour.
[whispering] Then let her resent.
[Simon moans lightly]
I shall do nothing of the sort.
My mother told me a lady is nothing
without her housekeeper.
I must make a good impression,
or nothing
in this house shall run smoothly.
Then I wish you well.
-Your Grace.
[chuckles]
[door opens, closes]
[knocking, door opens]
I have prepared the study
for you to work, Your Grace.
Jeffries, I am on my honeymoon.
The steward has left the records
in some disarray.
I cannot make head nor tail
of the estate's accounting,
and there are several letters
from farm tenants begging
an audience with Your Grace.
Very well! [groans]
If I must.
The castle was built in 1706
for Admiral Thomas,
a gift from Her Majesty Queen Anne--
For his military triumphs
against the French, I believe.
My younger sister Hyacinth
is something of a student of history.
Very well, Your Grace. Here we are.
The morning room,
where the former duchess
preferred to take tea with visitors.
My mama suggested
I extend an invitation to the vicar first.
-I believe she is right.
-Of course, Your Grace.
I look forward to hosting our first ball.
But I believe it would be prudent to wait
until after the close
of the London season, yes?
Indeed, Your Grace.
[chuckles]
And I shall look
at redecorating this room first.
You wish to redecorate?
Certainly, Your Grace.
There is to be a fair
in the village this week.
I offered it patronage on your behalf.
Most thoughtful of you, Mrs. Colson.
Perhaps we might give the servants
some time off to attend as well.
There is much to be done
now that the duke
and yourself are in residence.
Ah. Well, even more reason
to allow them some respite, then.
Is that…?
The former duchess, yes.
-She was beautiful.
-Thoughtful, too.
Most proper.
A perfect duchess.
Hmm.
And here is the nursery.
[chuckles lightly]
Your Grace?
-It is lovely.
-Mm.
Shall we move on?
I am certain there is much left to see.
Yes, of course.
Let me show you your grounds.
[Simon] My apologies. I--
Are we expecting royalty?
Begging your pardon, Your Grace.
The late duke preferred a formal table.
-But if you prefer--
-No.
No, never mind.
Mrs. Colson's tour today was exceptional.
The gardens are particularly lovely.
I found myself
in continual awe of their beauty.
Is anything wrong?
[scoffs] You…
You are so far away.
[chuckles] Well…
Well, that is easily remedied.
It is no trouble, truly.
[chuckles]
[Simon clears throat]
There, now. Much better, yes?
I thought perhaps
to redecorate a few rooms
but wished to talk to you first.
I'd hate to change anything
you're particularly attached to.
Then you may change it all.
In fact, please do.
[chuckles] Now, do not jest.
You must have fond memories…
or sentimental attachments.
After all,
this has been your home for many years.
Do what you will.
Paper the drawing room
in flamingo-pink tulle.
I am sure I shall love it.
You do know,
you need not dress so formally here.
Does this meet your approval?
Oh, without question.
[Daphne chuckles]
[sighs]
Your Grace, should we…
go upstairs?
I have a better idea.
[both laughing]
Where are we going?
Out.
[Daphne laughing]
[thunder crackles]
[both laughing]
[Simon laughing]
[Daphne gasping, moaning]
Do you like this?
Tell me what you want.
[shuddering breaths]
I want…
you.
[thunder booms]
[both gasping, moaning]
[Daphne moaning loudly]
[laughs, panting]
What?
Does that hurt?
-[laughs]
-When you…
No.
I feel as you feel,
absolutely wonderful.
[classical music playing]
[classical music continues]
[gasping]
[moaning lightly]
Wait!
Wait! Come here.
[both grunting, moaning]
-Whatever will the staff think?
-Does it matter?
[muffled grunting, moaning]
[muffled moaning]
[glass shatters]
[moaning continues]
-Ah!
-Ooh.
Apologies, Your Grace.
Well, our activities are quite… spirited.
I admit,
I did not even know it was possible.
I believed his physical inability
to have children would preclude him from…
…causing such difficult entanglements?
[both giggling]
Yes.
I am quite glad to say I was wrong.
[both laugh]
[both sigh]
[Benedict] He took your ribbon?
Did you take the ribbon?
-[Gregory] Dunno what you're talking ab--
-[Hyacinth] I saw him do it.
-[Benedict] I saw it in your pocket.
-[Hyacinth] It's not fair.
He does it every time.
-Just give it back.
-Gregory, stop!
-Good morning.
-Greg--
Morning, brother.
-Colin, your engagement is in Whistledown!
-Hyacinth!
[Hyacinth] What? It is!
-Very well. Everyone out, I think.
-[Violet] Yes.
I did say I was sorry.
I suppose I ought to be relieved
I found out before Lady Whistledown.
Mother, I have been courting
Miss Thompson all season.
Perhaps you were so taken up by Daphne
you failed to see it.
I knew you were flirting with her,
but you flirt with plenty of young ladies.
You always have, never in earnest.
-Until now.
-It is all happening so quickly.
I am not sure I have ever seen you
so solemn and serious.
No one ever takes me seriously,
except Marina.
I was not prepared to let
another of you fly the nest so soon.
Never fear, Mother.
You will still have your hands full.
-Especially with Eloise.
-[chuckles]
Good luck with that one.
[horses neighing]
Do you think
Colin will introduce us to his friends?
-Some of them are quite strapping.
-I am sure he will.
I am sure all of our fortunes
are about to change.
Mm. Especially Colin's.
-You look very lovely today, Penelope.
-Do not mock me.
It pains me you should think
every compliment a mockery.
Do not pity me, either.
I do not pity you, Penelope.
I respect you.
You have been a true friend
since I arrived here,
and I rely on your continued friendship
and sympathy.
My continued silence, you mean?
You think so little of me,
I cannot bear it.
I never would have made my way
through this awful tangle
without your kindness.
Please do not tell me you regret it.
I would never bring scandal
on you or our family,
if that is what you ask,
but I cannot condone your actions.
I want you as my friend, Pen.
Can you not try to understand
and be a little pleased for me?
Marina? Time for the modiste.
We must see to your trousseau.
-[scoffs] She is so lucky.
-[Prudence sighs wistfully]
A whole new wardrobe
and a handsome husband.
Between the two of them,
they will make the most beautiful baby.
He is not the father, you dunderhead!
-[both laughing]
-Oh, my goodness! I clean forgot.
Do not laugh at him!
She makes a fool of him already.
Ugh! You are no fun anymore.
Was I ever?
See? You will look so very lovely
with it pinned up next season.
No. I will look like
every other young lady,
except less graceful
and more bad-tempered.
Lady Bridgerton. Miss Eloise.
I understand we are here
on the matter of dropping our hems?
Precisely.
[Lady Featherington]
Lady Bridgerton! There you are.
Lady Featherington. Miss Thompson.
It is lovely to see you, Lady Bridgerton.
You must call me Violet now, I insist.
Is this not just delightful,
to know now
that our families will be joined forever?
Yes, it certainly is something.
[strained chuckle]
You must join us tomorrow night,
you, and dear Colin, and the viscount.
-We have so much to celebrate.
-I will certainly ask the viscount.
Perfect. Now, I shall need to steal
Madame Delacroix away for a moment.
[chuckles] I do apologize,
Lady Featherington,
but first there is the matter
of your account.
I was clear to your maid
that your line of credit--
Allow me to stop you there.
Our bills will be settled in full
as soon as you have made Miss Thompson,
soon-to-be Bridgerton,
her gown
and the other items for her trousseau.
I am afraid that is not possible.
Perhaps you might find another tailoress
more to your liking across town.
-Oui?
<span style="style1">-Madame Delacroix, that reminds me.
You have such a unique accent,
and yet I have never asked
where in France you're from.
[in French]
My mother was French, you see,
and I am not fooled by your little act.
I would hate
for the other ladies of the ton
to learn they have been taken in as well.
[in English] I believe Madame Delacroix
will be somewhat more amenable
to our requests now, Lady Featherington.
<span style="style2">Très bon?
-Très bon.
<span style="style1">-[Marina] Mm.
[attendees chattering]
[pigs snorting loudly]
What is the prize for the winner?
Why, slaughter, of course.
[Simon chuckles]
-[Simon clears throat]
-[Daphne] Ahem.
As the duke has granted me the honor
of opening our village fair
with this contest,
it is after careful consideration
that I have decided…
that all three pigs have tied!
[confused murmuring]
I hereby decree every pig such a winner
that none should be slaughtered.
[hesitant applause]
[maypole dance music plays]
They look lovely.
Look at those.
Why, these are delicious!
We must order some for Clyvedon.
Does your patronage extend
beyond pies, Your Grace?
The harvests on the farm have been poor,
and with the rents being tripled,
we are struggling
to put food on the table.
The rents tripled?
My steward did not inform me.
He hasn't shown his face
since your father passed,
God rest His Grace's soul.
He always gave his tenants
what they needed, unlike some.
Then it is a good thing indeed
that we are back at Clyvedon.
I am sure we can find a solution
to these difficulties,
and I thank you
for bringing them to our attention.
Your Grace.
[child whining]
-[child screeching, crying]
-Oh!
Oh, there, there, there, child.
No need to cry.
All is well.
My! You have a strong set of lungs.
They shall hear you all the way in London.
-If not all the way to France.
-[Daphne chuckles]
Oh, my goodness.
I must apologize, Your Grace.
Little Ada
has just discovered her own voice
and likes to use it
as often and loudly as she can.
Oh, um…
Oh, please, stand.
You should not be stooping
in your condition.
Well, it was lovely
to make your acquaintance.
Ada. [chuckles]
Oh!
Your Grace.
[Daphne] Mm.
What can we do about the farmer's rent?
There must be something.
I should have returned sooner
to see that things were in order.
I did not realize
my absence would be felt this way.
-Daphne--
-I hope that--
Please.
I only meant to say,
I hope it did not pain you too much
to see me with those children.
Pain <span style="style2">me?
Daphne, I thought only of you.
You know, oddly enough,
when I am actually
in the presence of children,
I forget all about my own concerns.
They are the easiest company in the world.
You are natural with them.
My younger sisters and brother.
Each one a mischief.
You know, my abundant family will be good
for at least one thing in future.
Eventually, they will all marry
and have children of their own,
and we will have more screaming infants
in our lives than we know what to do with.
[both laughing]
You will be a splendid aunt.
It thrills me that you are satisfied
with our married life as it is,
just the two of us.
I have all that I want just here.
How did I earn such luck?
That I do not know.
[Lord Featherington sighs]
Turn, please.
Profile.
Swish.
Swish!
Good. You have done well thus far,
Miss Thompson.
Tonight, I shall need to raise
the matter of a swift wedding.
[snickers loudly]
I am…
very sorry.
But this plan of yours, I find it wanting.
Deceiving Colin is one thing,
but being at close quarters
with his mother,
that is quite another.
Lady Bridgerton is shrewd.
She has had eight children.
Trust she knows when she is being managed.
What were your favorite pastimes
in the country?
I enjoyed riding above all else, my lady.
Please,
you must call me Violet now.
Remember?
Miss Thompson
is such a proper young lady, is she not?
Have you traveled at all
beyond England, Miss Thompson?
It has long been Colin's greatest ambition
to travel the world.
Never.
Though it is now
a great ambition of mine as well.
I am sensing a honeymoon in foreign parts.
What think you, Lord Bridgerton?
I would not like to speculate.
Yes, indeed. I believe a honeymoon
in foreign parts would be just the thing.
Mr. Bridgerton,
you might even make the most
of this fine weather we've been having
if you choose to marry
sooner rather than later.
Colin is still very young.
I believe
a lengthier engagement would be prudent,
excellent weather notwithstanding.
Mother, have I told you Miss Thompson
is very accomplished at needlework?
She is quite brilliant.
Puts my sisters to shame.
I can assure you, that is not true.
You have not seen
my sister Daphne's embroidery.
-In all honesty, it is like a battlefield.
-[Lady Featerhington laughs]
[Marina chuckles]
[Penelope slices loudly]
[off-key]
<span style="style2">♪ Oh dear, what can the matter be? ♪
♪ Oh dear, what can the matter be? ♪
♪ Johnny's so long at the fair ♪
♪ He promised he'd buy me
A bunch of blue ribbons ♪
♪ He promised to buy me
♪ Promised to buy me
A bunch of blue ribbons ♪
♪ To tie up my bonny brown hair ♪
♪ And it's oh dear… ♪
Colin?
Might I have a word?
Pen, of course.
[Prudence] <span style="style2">♪ What can the matter be ♪
♪ Oh dear ♪
It…
is a rather delicate matter.
I wish I did not have cause to raise it,
but I believe you deserve to know.
Is there something on my face?
Has it been there all evening?
It has, hasn't it?
Sorry. Um, go on.
I have wanted to talk to you
since the engagement was announced,
but we're always in company.
So, this is something about Marina?
Her heart belongs to another.
What?
His name is Sir George Crane.
He is a first son, a soldier.
They grew up
in neighboring properties in the country.
I am sorry,
but I have seen their love letters.
I felt you should know
before it was too late.
You really are very good. You know that?
Did you think that I would care
that she had fond feelings
for another before we met?
It would be rich of me,
considering I have flirted
with half the girls in London
at one point.
You misunderstand.
This was no mere flirtation.
Marina loves this man.
She loves him still.
And yet she is marrying me.
Trust me, Pen, do not fret.
I know my mind and Marina's.
We understand each other.
Oh. Have we moved the party
to the corridor?
You know, it is peculiar,
but the further I get
from that pianoforte,
the more like a party it feels.
Pen, your mother's asking for you.
[muffled music continues]
[tepid applause]
[Marina sighs deeply]
Is anything wrong?
Is it my brother? He…
He was odious at dinner. I apologize.
I cannot stand it, Colin.
My own father does not want me.
Even the Featheringtons
cannot wait to be rid of me.
Fool that I am, I truly thought
that with your family,
I might finally find acceptance.
But it is no use.
-Even your mother is just being polite.
-That is not true, Marina.
I am your family now.
We shall make our own family, you and me.
It is all I want.
It is all I want in all the world.
I wish we could be married
this very minute.
Then we could be alone together always.
I would never have to leave your arms.
-What if I told you there was a way?
-Colin, what are--
Scotland. Gretna Green.
I know it is mad,
but we could be married
within a matter of days.
We just have to make it to the border.
Anthony would be an ogre about it
when we first return, of course,
but by then, it would be too late.
We would be married. We would be together.
You hate the idea.
I love it.
I love you.
Allow me a day.
I shall arrange everything.
[sighs happily]
[sighs lightly]
-Ah. Here you are.
-Oh, good morning, dearest.
-The steward's books, I take it?
-Mm. I could not sleep.
Not even after last night's exertions?
[chuckles]
Would you care to break your fast with me?
I am sorry, my love.
The farmer in the village was right.
The estates have been neglected
far too long.
Wheat yields are down,
yet nobody uses the fields
for livestock grazing,
or rotate to a more plentiful crop.
-Is that not the steward's job?
-[angrily] They're my tenants, my people.
The responsibility is mine.
Please, excuse me. I have been staring
at these figures all morning.
Of course.
I suppose I have a good deal
to occupy myself with today too.
[Simon] Mm.
You know,
I mean to visit some of your tenants.
I might deliver some gift baskets and…
Are you missing home, Your Grace?
Do you think we have enough
for all the baskets?
Um, I should think so.
Your Grace!
Whatever are you…
I will have someone
gather those on your behalf.
One of the kitchen maids or the gardener.
Was no one available to assist you?
There is no need
to trouble anyone, Mrs. Colson.
We have it all in hand.
Do you intend to collect honey
from the hives in person as well?
[chuckles] Oh…
That might be a little beyond me.
If you simply tell me
of your wants and needs,
I will ensure everything is in order.
I will ensure everything is done properly.
-I shall keep that in mind.
-Mm.
Thank you, Mrs. Colson.
Mm-hmm.
Faith, she despises me.
She despises everybody.
Do not give it another thought.
[villagers chattering, laughing]
[Daphne] Hello.
Would you like a basket?
-There is--
-[villager clears throat]
A basket from Clyvedon?
Oh! A basket from Clyvedon?
-There is--
-[villagers whisper, indistinct]
Is something amiss?
Mama taught me it was tradition
for the new duchess to visit with gifts.
Well, I believe it is proper.
Should I have worn a different dress?
Or perhaps it signifies
I am high in the instep.
[Ada] Your Grace!
[Ada laughs]
Would you like a basket from Clyvedon?
There is bread and honey for the children.
Oh. You are too kind.
I would gladly take one
if I had means to carry it home.
Then we are determined to walk with you.
Oh, no. I didn't--
-I insist.
-No. Oh, I…
[sighs]
Perhaps I might ask
your opinion on something?
Of course.
Though, how I might
advise a duchess, I am not sure.
I feel that I have done something
to offend the village.
I know I am new to the role,
but I cannot imagine
what I have done wrong so soon.
-What?
-It was the pigs.
You said that all three pigs won.
At the fair?
I thought it the best outcome
for everyone.
It is tradition that the winner is allowed
to supply pork to Clyvedon
for the next year.
It's a great number of pigs, indeed.
When you could not choose a winner,
no farmer won the contract,
nor the income to go along with it.
-[Daphne gasps]
-Simply speaking, you, um…
You snubbed them.
I will correct my mistake at once. I…
I had no idea.
[sighs] How could you have, Your Grace?
What is all this?
Simon?
[man] Steady…
-Is everything well?
-Ah, Daphne. Yes.
I'm setting up work in the east wing.
-What's wrong with the study?
-[loud crash]
Careful!
You shall have to excuse me.
Your Grace.
Mrs. Colson?
Do you have a moment?
[Colson grunts lightly]
I know I have made some missteps
since I arrived.
My mother taught me a great deal
about being mistress of a household,
but I am not sure
either of us ever imagined
a house as grand as this one.
[Colson] Mm-hmm.
I am so very grateful for your guidance,
Mrs. Colson.
The truth is…
I fear the duke might not
be entirely at ease here at Clyvedon,
which is of course no reflection
of you or any of your staff.
-No. I-- I quite understand.
-You do?
Master Simon--
Eh… I beg your pardon. His Grace…
His childhood was not always easy.
After the death of my late mistress,
the duke lived almost exclusively
in London.
Do you mean to say
that Simon grew up here on his own?
We did our best to take care of him,
to mind him
as his mother would have wanted.
Of course you did.
[Colson] Mm.
The late duke
must have loved his wife very much
to have struggled so after her death.
Was it not a happy marriage, then?
It was strained.
He wanted an heir.
She wanted a child.
She kept trying
long after the doctors warned her not to.
Every month when her courses came,
it broke my heart to see her.
She was lucky to have you.
Everyone talked
as though it was her fault.
But how could they know that?
It is not always the woman who is barren.
Sometimes
it is the man's fault, of course.
Oh dear.
I am afraid I am speaking out of turn.
No. Not at all, Mrs. Colson.
Mm.
You were saying?
Well, I said to the duchess
what my mother said to me.
A womb cannot quicken
without strong, healthy seed.
And then, just as she was finally blessed
with Master Simon…
[sobbing] we lost her.
[knocking at door]
Why are you not dressed?
I told you we were dining
with Lady Gartside this evening.
[coughing, gasping]
Sorry, Mama. I'm not feeling well.
I ought to make you come along
to cough and splutter all evening.
It would serve Lady Gartside right.
She has been withholding
a dinner invitation from me, and now look…
Not a day
after Miss Thompson's announcement,
and they all come crawling.
[coughing]
Enjoy your evening, Mama!
[footsteps receding]
[sighs lightly]
[sighs]
[breathes deeply]
[suspenseful music plays]
[suspenseful music continues]
[suspenseful music intensifies]
[suspenseful music ends]
Penelope, what are you…?
-How dare you!
-Look.
Look at the signature
on Sir George's last letter,
and this one from many months ago.
-So?
-So, they are not the same.
The slant of the lettering,
it is all wrong.
-Penelope, I'm tired. I haven't--
-This one.
It was in a drawer
on the back of Mama's desk.
She or even Mrs. Varley
practiced George's signature,
but even they could not get it perfect.
That last letter,
the one where he broke your heart…
it was a forgery, Marina.
George never wrote those things to you.
He never denied loving you.
He never denied your child.
-Perhaps.
-Marina--
-Even if you are correct--
-I am correct. You cannot deny--
Even if it is true, George has
still not replied to my letters.
He has abandoned me,
while Colin has embraced me.
I thought you loved him.
George.
I was a fool.
This changes nothing.
Why is your bag packed?
Tell me you are not going to Gretna Green!
Marina! What will you do
when Colin realizes the child is not his?
That day will come. He is not simple.
What I will do
is live safe in the knowledge
that my husband is a good and kind man.
He would never turn me out on the street.
He will care for us both, come what may.
But what of him? What of Colin?
-You love him.
-What?
No, it makes sense now.
Your objections, your meddling.
You love Colin Bridgerton.
You know not of what you speak.
I believe I know
so much more than you, Pen…
of Colin, of the world.
If I am to be the executioner
of this childish infatuation,
then so be it.
Your love is an unrequited fantasy.
Colin sees you as you are
and regards you no differently
than he does Eloise,
or even little Hyacinth.
He sees me as a wife, a woman.
And as a woman,
I must make these difficult choices
for myself and for my child…
even if they hurt your feelings.
[door opens, closes]
Working late, Your Grace?
Curse it. What time is it?
[sighs]
These books seem
to have taken possession of you.
Those people rely on me to make a living,
to feed their families.
I should not have stayed away so long.
Why did you?
No particular reason.
Business in London.
But then I met this impertinent young lady
with a right hook
like an East End prizefighter.
I am serious.
As am I.
-Simon.
-Daphne.
[both breathing heavily]
[both grunting]
-[Daphne panting]
-[Simon grunting]
[Daphne exclaims passionately]
[both grunting]
[coins and books clatter]
[Simon gasping urgently]
[Simon exclaims, moans]
[exhaling sharply]
Ah!
[Simon panting loudly]
-We ought to clean up for dinner.
-Yes.
I'll meet you in the dining room.
[ominous music plays]
Your Grace!
These are the servants' quarters!
Where is Miss Nolan?
Your Grace, what is wrong?
You should have rung for me.
I need you to tell me something, Rose.
[breathing nervously]
How does a woman come to be with child?
-Y-Your mother--
-My mother told me nothing.
Please. No embarrassment.
Explain it to me, precisely.
[dramatic piano music plays]
[Simon] <span style="style2">It was such a simple solution.
[distant, echoing]
We can increase the harvest
if the farmers plant turnip.
On my travels, I encountered farmers
who tripled their income
by no longer rotating crops,
and instead, planting turnip,
and then turning out sheep to graze
and remove the weeds.
[dramatic piano music continues]
[Simon grunts, sighs]
[Daphne exhales deeply]
[Farmer Robert] <span style="style2">Thank you, Your Grace!
And please send
my great thanks to the duke!
He has purchased us
several cattle for the farm
so that we may rear livestock
until the soil is fertile again.
Our fortunes have been restored. [laughs]
Your Grace?
You may return to the house.
I wish to walk a while.
[dramatic piano music ends]
[clock ticking]
[footsteps approaching]
Are you ready for bed, my dear?
I believe I am.
♪ Keep your breath on me ♪
♪ And keep keep keep going
'Til my body is free ♪
[Simon panting]
♪ Keep your eyes on me ♪
♪ And keep keep keep going
'Til I'm the last thing you see ♪
[Daphne moaning]
♪ Keep your touch on my skin ♪
[both panting]
♪ Keep keep keep going
Keep keep keep going ♪
♪ Oh you're taking me down
Haunting my dreams ♪
♪ I'd like to end the world with you ♪
♪ You're taking me on
Haunting my heart ♪
♪ I'm at the end of the world with you ♪
♪ You're taking me down
Haunting my dreams ♪
[panting] Wait. Wait.
-[Daphne moans]
-Daphne…
Daphne…
[grunts]
♪ I'm at the end of the world with you ♪
[grunting forcefully]
[panting slows]
[both panting tremulously]
Daphne…
[Simon grunts]
Daphne.
[panting] Daphne.
Daphne!
Wh-Wh-What…
What did you do?
I had hoped it was not true.
I had hoped I was mistaken,
but clearly, I was not.
-How could you?
-How could I?
How could <span style="style2">I?
-You lied to me.
-I did not lie.
I trusted you.
I trusted you
more than anyone in this world,
and you took advantage.
You seized an opportunity.
And so I did the very same.
I told you I cannot give you children.
"Cannot" and "will not"
are two entirely different things.
You chose this for yourself.
You chose to lie to me.
I did not lie.
I thought you were prepared.
I thought you understood
how a child came to be.
You took my future from me,
the one thing I wanted more than anything.
You knew.
You knew that becoming a mother,
to have a family of my own one day,
you knew that was all I ever wanted.
I was prepared
to die on that dueling field
rather than marry you
and take your dream away.
I would have died for you.
You were the one
who insisted on this union.
You told me I was enough.
That was before I knew you.
Do you know, I even felt pity for you?
"Poor Simon," I thought.
"How it must pain him
to never know
what it is to be a father."
-I never asked for your pity.
-And I never asked for your betrayal!
-Daphne, I--
-You what?
You what?
You love me?
No, you most certainly do not.
You do not know the meaning of the word.
You do not lie to the one you love.
You do not trick the one you love.
You do not humiliate the one you love.
I may not know much,
as you have made abundantly clear,
but I do know one thing…
I know <span style="style2">that is not love.
[sighs]
[Lady Whistledown]
<span style="style2">All is fair in love and war,
but some battles leave no victor,
only a trail of broken hearts
that makes us wonder if the price we pay
is ever worth the fight.
[sighs]
The ones we love have the power
to inflict the greatest scars.
For what thing is more fragile…
than the human heart?
[sobbing]
[Eloise] Shh.
[Lady Whistledown] <span style="style2">The bond
<span style="style2">between man and bride is private, sacred.
But I must tell you,
I have learned
that a grave fraud is afoot.
What is it?
As if the Featheringtons
did not have enough to be dealing with,
Miss Marina Thompson is with child…
and she has been from the very first day
she arrived in our fair city.
Desperate times may call
for desperate measures,
but I would wager many will think
her actions beyond the pale.
Perhaps she thought it her only option,
or perhaps she knows no shame.
But I ask you,
can the ends ever justify
such wretched means?